Hello Asset Y Tribe, for the past few
days on our channel, many people have been asking us to explain a good health insurance
plan
.  Today, we are going to
break
down and review a popular plan in the health insurance industry in detail.  That is HDFC
Argo Health Insurance.  The highlights of this plan
are that it provides
2x benefits on the cover we take from day one,
along with a
50% no-claim bonus at the time of renewal and
unlimited restoration benefits beyond that
.  But
wait,
we can't blindly purchase health insurance just by looking at the highlighted features, because
insurance is full of clauses, sub-clauses,
terms, terminologies,
and hidden conditions.   That is
why we are going to discuss in great detail the types of this plan,
their benefits, features, whether
this plan really suits us, and if
so, the terms and conditions that we need to know about, and
all the important features related to this product that we need to know in this
video.
So watch the video till the end without skipping
.  I spent a lot of time researching for this video
.  I will try to present that
complete data to you within 15 minutes
.
So, since health insurance is something we claim at some point in our lives,
watch this video mindfully.  You will get full clarity
.  And many people
are watching videos but
forgetting to subscribe.  Don't forget to
subscribe, click on the bell icon next to it, and
turn on all notifications.  Because that
subscription may be free for you.  But it
gives us a little more boost to bring you such informative videos.
Let's log in before it's too late.  HDFC Ergo General
Insurance Company was established in 2002
.  This company is a joint venture between
HDFC Group, a leading financial entity in India,
and Ergo Group, one of the
largest insurance providers in Europe. In
addition to health insurance, HDFC Ergo
also offers different products such as motor, travel, home, and cyber insurance.
But the major part of the business is the health
insurance business. From 2002 to 2019,
HDFC Argu Group has been
growing tremendously.  But
when they
acquired Apollo Munich in 2020, they were able to add a lot to their customer
base as well as network hospitals
.   The
main reason why HDFC Argo Health Insurance is so
popular is the
benefits and features they offer.
Before we look at those features in detail, let's
go through a quick checklist.  This
checklist, which we are going to discuss, is not
only about this plan. No matter what health
insurance you are thinking of taking, you should
go through this checklist once.  First one is the claim
settlement ratio.
Claim settlement ratio is a
critical factor in the insurance world. Regardless of what kind of insurance you are
taking, check what the actual claim
settlement ratio is
.  And in this health insurance
industry, HDFC Argo has the best
claim settlement ratio numbers.  While the
industry average claim
settlement ratio is 78 to 86%,
HDFC ERGO is maintaining a claim settlement ratio of almost 98%
.  And besides that, data shows that 95% of
the claims are
settled within three months
.  And the
next important factor we need to check is the
incurred claims
ratio, which is the percentage of the premium amount collected that is
paid for these claims
.  Here too, the
industry average is 70-90%. If we
look at HDFC Argo's IICR, it is
86.41%, which is again healthy and
next, what we need to check is the
complaint volume, i.e. this parameter tells us
how many complaints are going to IRDI related to claims
.  And here too,
HDFC Argo has very low compliant volume
.  While the industry average for this complaint volume is
24 complaints for every 10,000 claims, data shows that for HDFC Argo,
this number is just 6 to 7 complaints
for 10,000 claims
.  So, even if you use
HDFC Argo, you will pass this checkpoint.  And the
next major and important checklist is
network hospitals. HDFC Argo
claims to have almost 15,000 plus cashless network hospitals across India.  And if we look at this same
number with a little more focus and
research in the Telugu states, we find that while
Telangana has almost 550 plus cashless
network hospitals, Andhra has
almost 400 plus network
hospitals.  So they are maintaining
very good cashless network hospitals in both Telugu states
.  And in case you want to check
how many network hospitals
are available in your city, I am
providing aggregator links below, so you can
check from there.  So, they have
very good cashless network hospitals available in both the Telugu states as well as India wide
.  This is
why they are able to provide hassle-free claims to policyholders
.  And in some emergency
cases, they say they process claims within 20 minutes
.  So
HDFC Argo is also a pass in network hospitals.   The
next important thing is reputation
and business credibility.
HDFC Argo has been in this business for many years
.  And
we all know how reputable the HDFC Group is in India.
And in addition to this, if we
look at the business part, we should check the solvency ratio
.  This solvency ratio
measures whether the insurance company has enough backup money to settle claims.  It is usually
better if this number is above 1.5.  HDFC
Argo maintains better numbers here too
.  Which is almost
1.68 HDFC Argo passes here too
.  So, if you want to take a screenshot of this five-point checklist,
try putting it here.   Not
only for this insurance, but also for
any other health insurance
.  Please check this five-point
checklist once.
Now let's get into the most important
part of the video. Features and
Benefits The health
insurance offered by HDFC Argo can be said to be a feature-rich product
.  Let's understand them in detail now
.  But before that, if you found
any of the information shared in the video useful, like the
video now.
And if you are not already subscribed to the channel, please
subscribe.
This plan is designed to offer comprehensive coverage along with innovative features
.  This means that this plan is designed to cover a wide range of
medical expenses
.
If you look at the main highlights of this comprehensive coverage, this plan covers everything from room rent, doctor's fees, medicines, and other medical services if you have a health issue and are
admitted to the hospital for at least 24
hours.
And in addition, this policy also covers all expenses related to pre-
and post-hospitalization charges, i.e., if you
are admitted to the hospital with any health concern, for
60 days before admission and up
to 180 days after discharge, whichever is applicable.
And not only that, this plan also covers all
day care
treatments like dialysis,
cataract surgeries, and chemotherapy
sessions, even if the hospital is open 24 hours a day.
In case you
want to receive treatment from home without being admitted to a hospital,
cover will be provided.  In
addition to these, ambulance and air ambulance
charges are also covered under this plan
.  And coming to other
important features, we do not have
any room rent limitations in this plan
.  We can choose the room we like
.  This is where HEFC Argo stands out when compared to the Optima
Select Plan and other health
insurance
.
We do not have any disease-wise sub-limits in this plan
.  This means that no
matter how much the expense is related to a disease, if it is
within our sum assured limit, it will definitely be covered
.  They
also provide up to 10,000 claims on annual health checkups
.  And
they also provide cover for treatments like Ayurveda and Siddha Homeopathy
.  And besides that,
they provide cover even if you are admitted to an Ayush hospital.   They
also offer certain discounts when purchasing plans and when renewing
.  They are also offering a
5% discount if you buy an In Case policy online, a 7.5% discount if you
pay two years' premiums in one go,
and a
10% discount if you purchase a three-year plan in one go
.  And in addition to that, critical
illness treatments like cancer
, heart-related diseases, and
modern
treatments like robotic surgeries are
also
covered in this plan.  There
are four types of health plans offered by NowHealth Argo.
Optima Select, Optima Secure,
Optima Super Secure and Optima
Restore.
Before looking at a detailed comparison of these plans, let's
take a look at how the point of restoration works.  This restoration
benefit is a highlight feature of this policy.
How this works is that if the
policyholder has any issue and makes a claim within a year,
that amount is immediately
restored. For example, in this policy, let's say the
sum assured or policy cover is 10
locks.  Even if an issue arises and
we claim that 10 lock amount,
another 10 lock will be
restored immediately.  Even if any other issue arises in the same year,
we can use those 10 lakhs
.  Whatever this registration benefit
is, whether it is claimed 100%
or partially, the amount will be
restored immediately
.  And this registration benefit,
whatever it is, is applicable to 100% of the sum insured in these three plans: Optima Secure, Optima
Super Secure, and Optima Restore.  But
this benefit is only applicable up to 10 locks of whatever Optima Select is available
.  Now let's compare these four plans in
detail.   The
first feature is the base cover
multiplier, which is limited in Optima Select
.  However,
in Optima Secure, 2x of the sum assured
amount is provided from day one
.  This means that
if our policy cover is 10,000,000, we will provide benefits up to 20,000,000 from day one
.  In case any
issue comes up and is admitted,
even if it is more than 10,000,000,
we will have protection up to 20,000,000.  However,
Optima Super Secure offers up to 3x
coverage.  And after this
two-year cover is over,
they also provide 5x cover from the third year
.  The same
benefit is available in Optima Super Secure and when it
comes to Optima Restore, there is a
multiplier benefit.
This 2x coverage is
provided only after two claim-free years.  This means that if no claims are made for two years,
this 2x coverage will apply from the third year onwards.
That is also a due to no claim bonus.  And if we
look at the next important feature, it is the
restoration benefit that we discussed earlier
.  If you look at this in Optima Select,
this restoration benefit is only
available up to 10,000.  And there is the automatic restore seen in Optimus Secure and
Optima Super Secure
.  This means that
100% of the base sum assured will be
restored if used in case of an in-case situation
.  And Optima Restoran
also provides a 100% registration benefit
.  And the next
important feature is the no claim bonus.
How this no-claim bonus works is that if we do not make
any claims in the first year after taking out the policy,
then
50% of the sum assured amount will be added
to our cover under the no-claim bonus
.  For example, if our policy
cover amount is 10,000,000, and
we do not make any claims in the first year, an additional
5,000,000 will be added in the second year
.  In case no claim is made in the second year,
then
another Rs. 500,000 will be added.
Then the total cover amount will
be 20,000.  This no-claims bonus
provides up to 100%.  This means that after the
10,000,000 cover is locked, this no-claim
bonus is not yet applicable.  So
if you look at this no claim bonus, it is being
provided at 50% for all plans
.  Up to it reaches 100% of
the cover amount.  And the next
important thing we see is that
only in Room Rent Optima Select, we have a
private AC room limitation
.  The remaining plans, namely Optima
Secure, Optima Super Secure,
and Optima Restore, do not have any room
rent limit.
We can turn off any room.  And next daily
hospital cash and pre and post
hospitalization charges are
available in all plans
.  And
you can see the rest of the important features here.
So we can understand this simply
.  Whatever Optima Select is,
it's like a budget-friendly or entry-level
plan.
We can customize some options to our liking.
But
we can consider the Optima Secure and Super Secure plans as advance level plans
.  We can get 2x and 3x coverage
from day one.
Optima Restore also has this coverage,
but there are some limitations.
So, I hope you completely understand the difference between these four plans
.  And in case you're
looking to purchase this plan, let's see how it goes.
But before that, we need to check if there are some important features when we purchase a plan
.  Let's discuss it very
quickly.
Make sure there is no pre-existing condition option before taking out first health insurance.  If there is a copay option,
we will have to pay a certain amount after the bill is generated
.  So, don't enable the copayment option just because it will reduce the premium
.  After that, you should also check whether there are any restorative and
no claim bonus benefits
.  And
then the room rent limit.  In case our
policy only provides rooms with a low limit and we
opt for luxury rooms when we are admitted to the hospital without our knowledge, we will have to pay that fee ourselves
.  So be sure to know what the room rent limit is
.  After that, the
important thing is the consumable cover.
Under this cover, health insurance also covers all the different consumables used during treatment, such as cotton
swabs, gloves,
syringes, masks, and gowns.
Remember, in case there is no rider or this Yed-on, we will have to pay that amount ourselves.
And while undergoing treatment in ICU,
these consumables,
whatever they are, are still expensive
.  And the next important feature
we need to look for is whether there is a pre- and post-
hospitalization benefit or not, as well as
advance treatment cover.
In recent times, cancer and other
advanced diseases are becoming very common
.  So, check whether
these are covered by your health insurance or not
.  And then the waiting
period can be up to two to three years for some diseases
.  Check clearly what those diseases are
.  And last and
most important thing is honesty. Disclose
any pre-
existing conditions related to your health without missing a beat
.
This is often the main reason why claims are rejected.   They continue to
take out health insurance without disclosing that the premium will be high.  But if, when we investigate before making a claim, it
turns out that they are already pre-existing,
we will not have any claim.
We will lose a lot because of that.  So, don't forget to disclose any
conditions or history of surgery
.   If you
want to take this policy now, I am putting a referral link
in the description and comment section below
.  Again, this is
not a promotion.  That's just a referral link
.  If you find this video helpful, you can
take it from there
or take it anywhere.  Once you
click on that link, you will land on this page
.  Once you land on this page, it
will first ask for your gender and also your family details.
In case you are an individual, you can
select "Self" and proceed
.  Or if
there are family members, you can add yourself along with your wife, and
in case there is no wife, only the father and
mother, and in case there are kids, you can
also add them.  So,
select the details on this page and
continue typing, it will ask for your age here
.  So after selecting the age and
hitting continue, it will ask you what your city is.
Select the city.  And
after that, it will ask for your full name and mobile
details, fill them in.
After that, it will ask about your medical history
.  Here, if you have
any existing diseases, select them,
or select None of these
.  And then it asks if you already have
any health insurance
.  Here, in case your office
provides you with any health insurance, you
can select Yes here.
Otherwise, select no insurance
.  If you click on View Plans
and scroll down a bit,
you will see HDFC Ergo Plans here.  If you
click on it, you will
see the four plans we have discussed so far.   You
can choose whichever plan is affordable for you.  But the
Optima Super Secure, as
we discussed earlier,
requires you to pay a premium for three years, so the
premium here is obviously higher.
After selecting the plan that suits you,
click on the Customize Plan option here.  Click
here to
see the options to change the plan and the amount
covered
.  So Optima Secure
provides 2x cover, so if you
select 10 lock cover here, it is
shown here that it provides another 10 lock benefit as an extra.  So if you drag down a little here,
you
will see an option called Riders.  You can add any of those riders you
like and
ignore them if you don't like them.
And here you will see an option called Aggregate Deductibles
.  In case it is
applied and you have enabled the copy, in
that case
you will have to pay some amount after the bill is generated
.  So if that's the case, don't
try to apply.  And
after that, there will also be top ups.  In case you
need more than 20,000,000 cover, you can add
top-up plans without increasing the cover
.  How these top-ups work
is that if there are any expenses exceeding Rs. 20,000,
then this cover will be
helpful.  Otherwise, these won't be of
much use.  So, after
adding the riders and options you like, the
premium will appear here.  Once you
type "Proceed to Proposal", you will
land on this page.  Here, you will need to
enter your family details and your details correctly and
make the payment.   Once the
policy is approved, there
is a free look period of up to 15 to 30 days.  In case of a mistake,
you
can rectify it.  And in case you have any doubts or are
not able to complete the process, the
Policy Bazaar team will call you and
assist you.  And
in some areas, agents will come directly to your
home, explain the plan in detail, and
even
help with the purchase.  And
they will also help you with the claims process
.  And the premiums, if any,
differ based on your age and health condition.
When there are elderly persons in a family plan, it is a
better option to take out a separate policy for them.  So overall, if you look at the
pros and cons of this plan,
you will find good
network hospitals and claim
settlement ratio in this plan.
Along with that, they are also providing 2x coverage restoration benefit
and no claim bonus
.  And HDFC Group is
very reputable and reliable and
this
plan also provides us with flexible options.
And looking at the negatives,
HDFC Ergo
plans are a bit more expensive when compared to other plans
.  It is expensive, so we are able to provide our
claims and other benefits as well
.  So, if you
compare the premiums with other plans, you can
say that it is a slight disadvantage.  And besides, Hefc Argo
does not provide any maternity cover.  If you
also want to get In Case Family Insurance maternity cover, you will need to
explore other options
.  And any
outpatient expenses that may be incurred will not be
covered by the plan.  For that, you will need to
top up or
explore other plans
.  And
if there are any major exclusions related to this policy, that is, in
what cases a claim is
not made, please
pause and read them in detail, as they are displayed on the screen.  If
we look at the major ones,
any injury in adventure sports,
alcoholic or other treatments, etc., are not
covered.  And as
mentioned in the disadvantages,
maternity and outpatient
consultations, if any, are
not covered by the plan.  And
if there are any other exclusions,
read them all here so you don't miss out.
Because health insurance
doesn't cover all claims.
Claims will only be made for those they mentioned
.  So, if you're thinking of taking this policy overall, let's
take a quick look at which plan suits whom.  Money is
not a problem.
If I want full protection for my family, it is better to take Optima Secure
or Super Secure plans
.  In case
you want better protection at a slightly more affordable price,
Optima Restore is a better option.
In
case you
want a health plan with limited benefits with complete customization, you should
choose Optima Select and
customize it
.  Overall, this is a
complete review of HDFC Ergo, but I will try to cover
all the important terms and conditions, features, and more
.  All of them are
also mentioned in detail in the policy document
.
Try reading it once.  And if
any of our subscribers
are holding this health plan, please try to tell us about your
experience, whether good or bad,
in the comments section below
.  That would help all of our audiences as well
.  And
before taking out a policy,
try to clarify all your questions as much as possible, rather than taking it blindly.
So, while
this is one of the best products among the health plans available in the market,
it is
not the best.  In case the premiums
seem expensive, you can also explore other plans on the same page shown above
.  In case you're exploring something else,
try checking the checklist we talked about earlier.  So this is a
complete review of HDFC Ergo,
in case you
want a review related to any term plan, then drop a comment
in the comment section below saying Neet Term Plan
.  In case we
get more than 100 comments this week,
we will try to cover that video as soon as possible.  And if you found the video informative,
like the video and
subscribe to the channel.  Please try to
share this video with your friends and family
.
See you again with another video.  Bye bye take care